# Dharaneesh Anthikapalli

- dharaneeshoffl2001@gmail.com
- 7383849310
- 12/07/2001
- Indian
- in linkedin.com/in/dharaneesh-anthikapalli-4531b1194
- github.com/Dharaneesho9
- 9 39-33-15/12/6 Vuda Colony, Madhavadhara, 530018 Visakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh, India

## **Professional Summary**

Seeking a fresher's role to improve and utilize my technical knowledge gained at VIT University in the last three years. I'm presently pursuing my Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, and I have scored really well. I have done other internships and projects that have quite helpful technical solutions for modern-day problems.

## **Education**

2019 – 2023 Vellure Institute of Technology, Chennai,

Tamilnadu, India Bachler of Technology, Computer Science with Cyber Physical Systems 🗆

present CGPA is 9.01

2017 – 2019 Sri Chaitanya Educational Institutions, Hyderabad, 12th

Telangana, India Passed out with a score of 97.3%

2017 Shri Swaminarayan Gurukul International School, Medak, CBSE

Telangana, India Passed out with 10 CGPA

# **Professional Experience**

07/2021 – 09/2021 **Tecogno Solutions,** Software Developer Intern

- Developed a 3D model which scales itself to resemble a person's body
- Created programs that can read the information from the forms of old times and makes csv files out of them for digitalisation of past data

06/2021 – 07/2021 **The Sparks Foundation,** Data Science and Business Analytics Intern

• Made Decision Tree Classifier Model

07/2020 – present **HackClub VIT, Chennai,** Blackbox automator

a community of enthusiastic people, good at various trending technologies

07/2019 – present **PALS VIT, Chennai,** Student Event Manager

- Demonstrated respect, friendliness, and willingness to help whenever needed
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions

#### **Certifications**

 Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner ☑ • Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure [7]

## **Projects**

11/2021 - 03/2022 **Sociommerce** 

The project is a website, made from scratch, which has the features of both social media and e-commerce, it is implemented using React for frontend, Django for backend, MySQL for database management, it is hosted using AWS.

management, it is nosted using Aw S

08/2021 – 12/2021 Analysis of Impact of Water Quality on Crop Production

This is a data analysis work, where we analyzed the effects that chemicals in water at different states had on the crops they produced, done using RStudio

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Impact-of-water-on-crop-production-using-R

08/2021 - 12/2021 **Context Aware Smart Bus** 

This program is capable of making a bus, aware of the environment around it and what happened in the past and could take intelligent decisions to get the best out of the situation, assuming that it is provided with required hardware

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Context-Aware-SmartBus-Java

01/2021 - 04/2021 **3D User Manual Using Unity** 

In the project, we create an application that is capable of elucidating your products at the next level, so basically, the application is capable of explaining your product in the 3D space virtually through your phone, where you exactly know what your manual is trying to explain about

01/2021 - 03/2021 Target Spotter using PSO and OpenCV

it uses an AI-based computing technique, i.e Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO). An image processing technique is used to find the features of the image which is the ORB algorithm, then KNN algorithm for matching them, and Operating system related multiprocessing techniques are used for enabling parallel computing for faster computation. All these techniques are integrated together to get the task done.

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Target-spotter-Using-PSO-and-OpenCV

### Skills

Python(mainly sklearn, Flask, bpy,cv2, C++

Django)

HTML, CSS, Javascript and php

JAVA

Simulink

Git and GitHub

Used for Controller design

Matlab Arduino

Micro Controller

Ptolemy SQL

Languages

English
 Hindi
 Telugu